Guide to the John Holker Papers GEN MSS 2092
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence and Other Papers, 1777–1821; 1; 9.5 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
  - Marmié, Peter
    - Letters to John Holker, 1791–1812 (Box 3, Folder 164-165)
      Primarily regarding Jacobs Creek Iron Works.
    - Letters to Thomas FitzSimons, 1786 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - Memorandum of loan office certificates loaned to Pennsylvania, [1778-1780] (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - Observations on Mr. [Thomas] Ross's charges, 1783 (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - Receipts and sight drafts, 1778–1784 (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Mery & La Case et fils, 1783 (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Meulan d'Ablois family
    - Letter to John Holker regarding Meulan d'Ablois family interests [signature illegible], 1778 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Meulan d'Ablois, Marguerite. Letter to John Holker, 1778 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Meulan d'Ablois, Marie-Pierre-Charles. Letters to John Holker, 1779–1780 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Meulan d'Ablois, Marie-Pierre-Charles. Power of attorney to John Holker and Martin Oster, 1778 (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Meulan d'Ablois, Marie-Pierre-Charles. Registered claims related to the ships Le Laboulaye, La Jeune Rose, La Duchesse de Morthemart, Le Diligent, and La Marquise de Cassini, 1778 (Box 7, Folder 318)
    - "Tableau général" related to shipping interests of Madame Meulan or her heirs and M. Rambaud, circa 1779 (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Miralles, Juan de, 1779, undated (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Mitchell, John
    - Account current with John Holker, 1782 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - Accounts with French navy, receipt and certificates for horses supplied to French army, 1780–1781 (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Itemized statement of transactions furnishing equipment for Rochambeau's army, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 319)
  - Monbos & Latil, 1780 (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Moncreiff, Archibald, 1782–1789 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Morris, Gouverneur, 1779 (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Morris, Robert
    - "Copy of the letter wrote … to Mr. Holker dated Philadelphia [the] 26th of February 1784" [64 pages], undated (Box 7, Folder 320)
    - Letter to Mark Pringle, 1782 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Letter to William Smith, 1780 (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - Letters to John Holker, 1782–1786 (Box 4, Folder 184-185)
    - Memorandum relating to loan office certificates in 1778, undated (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - Moylan, J., 1783–1784 (Box 4, Folder 187)
    Includes invoice related to the Empress of China.
  - Mumford, Thomas, 1790 (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Munnikhuysen, John, 1788 (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - "N-O" General, 1779–1803 (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Némoutier [first name unknown], 1819 (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - Nesbitt (Jonathan) & Co., 1781 (Box 8, Folder 321)
  - Oster, Martin
    - Deposition related to ships Marie Françoise and Liverpool (copy), 1781 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - Draft letter to unidentified correspondent concerning dispute over the ship Intéressant, 1780 (Box 4, Folder 193)
    - Financial records, 1780–1782 (Box 4, Folder 194)
    - Letters to John Holker, 1780 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - Memorandum of salary for his services at the Philadelphia consulate, 1779–1780 (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - "P-R" General, 1780-1788, undated (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - Parker (Daniel) & Co.
    - Assignment and deed of trust to Thomas FitzSimons by Parker, John Holker, and William Duer (copy), 1784 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Bill of exchange, 1783 (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - Financial records, 1783–1784 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - Letter to George Joy, 1789 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Memorandum of agreement with Robert Morris, 1783 (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - Pennell, Joseph, 1779 (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - Peters, Thomas, 1780–1786 (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Pinckney, Thomas. Circular letter, signed, to Delaware Governor Thomas Collins informing him of South Carolina's ratification of the United States Constitution, 1788 (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - Plombard, J. [consul of France at Charleston], 1779 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    Letters to Conrad Alexandre Gérard and Holker.
  - Pringle, Mark. Letters to John Holker, 1782-1790, undated (Box 4, Folder 207-212)
  - Pringle, Mark. Memorial to United States Circuit Court and bill of complaint against William Duer, 1807 (Box 4, Folder 213)
    Copy, addressed jointly with John Holker.
  - Quesnel, Per [possibly Elisabeth's father], 1804 (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - Read, James and Will Winder Jr., 1779 (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - Reculès de Basmarein & Raimbaux, 1778–1779 (Box 4, Folder 216)
    Primarily letters to Roulhac & Cie.
  - Reed, Joseph, 1780 (Box 4, Folder 217)
  - Rendon, Francisco, 1784 (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - Ricot, Philippe Nicolas, 1778 (Box 4, Folder 219)
  - Ridley, Matthew
    - Accounts with John Holker, John Williams, William Turnbull, circa 1780s-1790 (Box 8, Folder 322)
    - Letters to John Holker, 1780–1789 (Box 4, Folder 220-222)
    - Sundry goods shipped, 1783 (Box 8, Folder 323)
  - Ridley & Pringle
    - Correspondence, 1782–1787 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Financial records, 1780–1783 (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Financial records, 1784–1790 (Box 9, Folder 350)
  - Roche [first name unknown], 1778–1779 (Box 5, Folder 225-226)
    Letters and contract to Holker.
  - Ross, John
    - Account with owners of the ship Patsey Rutledge (formerly Artois), 1785 (Box 8, Folder 324)
    - Accounts and invoices to John Holker, 1782–1795 (Box 9, Folder 351)
    - Accounts and invoices related to the brig Black Prince, 1782–1789 (Box 9, Folder 352)
    - Claim against John Holker, 1796–1798 (Box 5, Folder 227)
      Unsigned letter to unnamed "Gentlemen" and copy of award granted from Massachusetts [?] Supreme Judicial Court.
    - Letter to Ralph Bowie, 1789 (Box 5, Folder 228)
    - Letters to Daniel Parker & Co. and Parker, Duer and Co., 1782–1783 (Box 5, Folder 229)
    - Letters to John Holker, 1785–1799 (Box 8, Folder 325)
    - Statements to owners of the ship Dolphin, 1781–1783 (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Russell, Thomas
    - Financial records, 1781–1790 (Box 5, Folder 231)
    - Letters to John Holker and Thomas FitzSimons, 1782–1796 (Box 5, Folder 232)
    - Sales of indigo, 1782 (Box 8, Folder 326)
  - Rutledge, John, 1780 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - "S" General, 1781–1819 (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Sabatier fils & Després, 1780 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - Sabatier fils & Després, undated (Box 8, Folder 327)
  - Sarazin & Cie., 1783–1784 (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - Selles [first name unknown], 1782–1783 (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - Slough, Mathias (Continental commissary), 1781–1784 (Box 8, Folder 328)
  - Smith, William
    - Account with ship Defence, 1780 (Box 8, Folder 329)
    - Accounts with John Holker, 1780–1786 (Box 8, Folder 330)
    - Accounts William Turnbull & Co., Robert Morris, Forman & Chambers, 1781–1787 (Box 8, Folder 331)
    - "Balance of General account rendered … to the Honble John Holker Agent General for the Royal Marine", 1783 (Box 8, Folder 332)
    - Financial records, 1783–1784 (Box 5, Folder 238)
    - General account for ship Defence, 1779 (Box 5, Folder 239)
    - Itemized account of horses sold to Holker for account of de Corny for French troops commanded by Rochambeau, 1780 (Box 8, Folder 333)
    - Letter to Matthew Clarkson, Tench Coxe, Patrick Morris, 1786 (Box 5, Folder 240)
    - Letters to John Holker, 1779–1787 (Box 5, Folder 241-245)
    - Letters to Robert Morris, 1779 (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - "Sales of Damaged Flour for Acc't of Royal Marine of France" [one statement signed by F. Yates], 1785 (Box 8, Folder 334)
    - Sales of sundry bills of exchange drawn by John Holker for the account of the French Royal Marine, 1783 (Box 8, Folder 335)
  - Société d'émulation de Rouen, pour le progres des sciences, lettres et arts, 1801 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - St. Hilaire [possibly St. Hilaire Begorrat], 1783 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - St. Limozen [first name unknown], 1783 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Stonestreet, Félicité Julie, 1782 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - Stroud, William. Invoices of ammunition, wagons, horses, and equipment for Rochambeau's army, 1780 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - "T-W" General, 1778–1798 (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - Tardiveau frères and Tardiveau frères & Lacassagne, 1783–1784 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - Terrasson, Barthélémy, 1779–1781 (Box 5, Folder 254)
    Includes letters to Anne-César de La Luzerne, Holker.
  - Terrasson frères & Cie., circa 1780-1784 (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - Turnbull, William and William Turnbull & Co.
    - Accounts of disbursements made on the order of Holker for the French army and disbursements and outfitting brig Hope, 1781 (Box 8, Folder 336)
    - Accounts of sales, undated (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 355)
    - "Copy of remarks on Mr. Wm. Smith's acc't with [the] royal marine of France", 1782 (Box 8, Folder 337)
    - Financial records, 1780–1785 (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - Letters and accounts to John Holker, 1786–1798 (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - Turnbull, Marmié & Co., 1784 (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - Turnbull, Marmié & Co., 1802 (Box 9, Folder 353)
  - Usher, Thomas, 1780 (Box 8, Folder 338)
  - Valnais, Joseph de, 1786
    - Account of payments related to French prisoners, 1778 (Box 5, Folder 259)
    - Letter to Conrad Alexandre Gérard, 1779 (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - Letter to unidentified recipient, 1779 (Box 5, Folder 261)
      References Lafayette, frigates Alliance, La Deane, and Elizabeth, and French prisoners.
    - Letters to John Holker, 1778–1781 (Box 5, Folder 262-264)
  - Veillon, L., 1778 (Box 5, Folder 265)
    Bill related to provisioning the schooner Lively; includes note from Holker to Robert Morris.
  - Verdier, Jean Baptiste, undated (Box 5, Folder 266)
  - Veuve Lalanne & fils, 1779 (Box 5, Folder 267)
    Power of attorney to Holker
  - Webb, William, 1785 (Box 5, Folder 268)
    Protested bill of exchange of Jacques-Donatien Leray de Chaumont on Holker
  - Whiteside, Peter and Peter Whiteside & Co., 1779-1783, undated (Box 5, Folder 269)
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1779–1780 (Box 5, Folder 270)
  - Wilson, Henry. Deposition of Britingham Dickeson related to schooner Dolphin, 1783 (Box 5, Folder 271)
  - Wilson, James. Letters to John Holker, 1779–1780 (Box 5, Folder 272)
  - Wilson, James. "Opinion concerning a power necessary to be given to the Consul of France", 1779 (Box 5, Folder 273)
  - Wyckoff, Hendrick, 1781 (Box 5, Folder 274)
  - Zollickoffer, Jean Conrad, 1779 (Box 5, Folder 275)
  - Unidentified author. Draft letter to Committee of Provisions concerning the ship Defence, undated (Box 5, Folder 276)
  - Unidentified author. Memorandum listing correspondence of Peter Marmié, William Duer, and others, circa 1782 (Box 5, Folder 277)
- Catalog Cards, undated; 2; 1 Linear Feet (1 box)
  This series contains typed catalog cards describing Series I, arranged in chronological order. The materials were created by the Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library at an unknown date.
  Materials maintain order found at time of acquisition.
  - Catalog cards, undated (Box 11, Folder 356-368)